A Guide to the Rockefeller University records, President, Detlev Bronk, General Professional correspondence FA914
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller University records, President, Detlev Bronk, General Professional correspondence
1925-1975
Rockefeller Archive Center
Bronk, Detlev W. (Detlev Wulf), 1897-1975
Rockefeller University
Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research
FA914
7.92 Cubic Feet 18 document boxes
18 document boxes.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note
Materials requiring specialized equipment for access (film, audio, video, slides) may be closed to research dependent on availability of the applicable equipment
Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be closed to researchers at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/Head of Reference.
File Plan note
Former Classification: I 303-1
Arrangement
General Professional correspondence is arranged Alphabetical order.
Arrangement
The Rockefeller University records, President, Detlev W. Bronk materials are arranged into 4 components:
Administrative papers (FA140)
General and Professional correspondence (FA914)
Biographical and Personal Material (FA964)
Personal and Professional papers (FA965)
Other Finding Aids
FA140 Rockefeller University records, President, Detlev W. Bronk, Administrative papers.
FA964 Rockefeller University records, President, Detlev W. Bronk, Biographical and Personal material.
FA965 Rockefeller University records, President, Detlev W. Bronk, Personal and Professional papers.
Conditions Governing Access note
Material is open for scholarly research.
Aviation medicine; Biology -- Research; Medical research; Physiology; Operations management; Medical sciences; Bronk, Detlev W. (Detlev Wulf), 1897-1975; Unesco; Rockefeller University; National Research Council. (U.S.); National Science Foundation. (U.S.); Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research
- General professional correspondence, 1925-1975; 7.92 Cubic Feet
  - Abb-Adl (Box 1)
  - Ads-Amb (Box 1)
  - Amer. A.-Amer. J. (Box 1)
  - Amer. L.-Amer. M. (Box 1)
  - Amer. N.-Amer. Phi (Box 1)
  - Ameri: Phy.- Ami (Box 1)
  - And-Arm (Box 1)
  - Arn-Az (Box 1)
  - Aydelotte, Frank, 1925-1935 (Box 1)
  - Bagarotti, Giovanni and Cornelia, 1957-1970 (Box 2)
  - Bac-Barr (Box 2)
  - Bart-Baz (Box 2)
  - Beadle, George, 1961-1969 (Box 2)
  - Bean-Bell (Box 2)
  - Belt, Benj (Box 2)
  - Bennett, Thomas Peter, 1970-1975 (Box 2)
  - Best, Charles H., 1933-1975 (Box 2)
  - Benn-Bha (Box 2)
  - Bid-Bit (Box 2)
  - Bla-Borde (Box 2)
  - Bordl-Boz (Box 3)
  - Bra-Brin (Box 3)
  - Bris-Brow (Box 3)
  - Brimble, L.J.F., 1955-1965 (Box 3)
  - Bru-Bun (Box 3)
  - Bur-By (Box 3)
  - Busser, John H., 1959-1961 (Box 3)
  - Cad-Cap (Box 3)
  - Calder, Lord Ritchie, 1962-1973 (Box 3)
  - Cambridge Instrument Co., 1929-1931 (Box 3)
  - Cannon, James M. and James M. IV, 1971-1975 (Box 3)
  - Card-Carr (Box 4)
  - Cart-Caw (Box 4)
  - Cazier, Mont A., 1954-1960 (Box 4)
  - Ce-Cham (Box 4)
  - Chan-Cit (Box 4)
  - Chance, Britton, 1935-1970 1971-1975; 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Cl (Box 4)
  - Coa-Cole (Box 4)
  - Coli-Com (Box 4)
  - Con (Box 4)
  - Coo-Cox (Box 5)
  - Cornell, S. Douglas, 1953-1975 (Box 5)
  - Cra-Cu (Box 5)
  - Dal (Box 5)
  - Dal-Davie (Box 5)
  - Davis-Day (Box 5)
  - Dea-Dei (Box 5)
  - Dek-Dew (Box 5)
  - Denworth, Raymond K., 1933-1934 (Box 5)
  - Dib-Dol (Box 5)
  - Dolman, Claude E., 1953-1968 (Box 5)
  - Don-Dow (Box 5)
  - Dra-Dub (Box 6)
  - Dud-Dy (Box 6)
  - Ea-Eg (Box 6)
  - Edelman, Gerald M., 1968-1975 (Box 6)
  - Ei-Em (Box 6)
  - Eisenhower, Dwight; Milton; John S., 1949-1975 (Box 6)
  - En-Ex (Box 6)
  - Erlanger, Joseph, 1930-1965 (Box 6)
  - Fa-Fe (Box 6)
  - Fi-Fl (Box 6)
  - Flexner, Abraham, 1927-1964 (Box 6)
  - Flexner, Simon, 1922 1956-1957 (Box 6)
  - Foc-Foo (Box 6)
  - For-Fox (Box 6)
  - Fortune, 1954-1955 (Box 7)
  - Fra-Fus (Box 7)
  - Fruton, Joseph F., 1954-1956 (Box 7)
  - Fulton, John F., 1930-1935 1953-1954 (Box 7)
  - Ga (Box 7)
  - Gasser, Herbert S., 1931-1953 (Box 7)
  - Ge (Box 7)
  - Gerard, Ralph W., 1929-1974 (Box 7)
  - Gi-Gl (Box 7)
  - Go (Box 7)
  - Golden, William T., 1959-1975 (Box 7)
  - Gra (Box 7)
  - Granit, Ragnar, 1933-1959 (Box 7)
  - Granit, Ragnar, 1960-1975 (Box 8)
  - Gre-Gri (Box 8)
  - Gregg, Alan, 1929-1964 (Box 8)
  - Gro-Gw (Box 8)
  - Hab-Han (Box 8)
  - Handler, Philip, 1959-1975 (Box 8)
  - Hap-Harvey, A. McG (Box 8)
  - Harrison, Wallace K., 1957-1975 (Box 8)
  - Hartline, Keffer, circa 1934-1968 (Box 8)
  - Harvey, E. Newton, 1929-1961 (Box 8)
  - Has (Box 8)
  - Has-Haz (Box 8)
  - Hea-Her (Box 8)
  - Hecht, Selig, 1930-1957 (Box 9)
  - Hes-Hey (Box 9)
  - Hia-Hil (Box 9)
  - Him-Hit (Box 9)
  - Hoa-Hop (Box 9)
  - Hollaender, Alexander, 1968-1973 (Box 9)
  - Hor-Hox (Box 9)
  - Hu (Box 9)
  - Huxley, Julian, 1955-1958 1975 (Box 9)
  - I (Box 9)
  - International Physiological Congress, 1935 (Box 9)
  - Ja-Je (Box 9)
  - Jo-Ju (Box 9)
  - Journal of Cellular and Comparative Physiol, 1951-1952 (Box 9)
  - Ka (Box 10)
  - Ke (Box 10)
  - Ki (Box 10)
  - Kl-Ko (Box 10)
  - Klopsteg, Paul E., 1956 1974 (Box 10)
  - Kr-Ku (Box 10)
  - Kubie, Lawrence S., 1951-1963 (Box 10)
  - La (Box 10)
  - Laurence, William L., 1956-1975 (Box 10)
  - Le (Box 10)
  - Li (Box 10)
  - Livingston, Robert B., 1953-1975 (Box 10)
  - Lo (Box 10)
  - Lu-Ly (Box 11)
  - McC-McH (Box 11)
  - McK-McV (Box 11)
  - Mab-Mal (Box 11)
  - Man-Mar (Box 11)
  - Marconi International Fellowship, 1972-1975 (Box 11)
  - Marine Biological Laboratory, Woods Hole, 1927-1934 (Box 11)
  - Mas-May (Box 11)
  - Mea-Mel (Box 11)
  - Men-Mey (Box 11)
  - Menaker, Walter, 1954-1973 (Box 11)
  - Mic-Mir (Box 11)
  - Michigan Memorial-Phoenix Project, 1950 (Box 11)
  - Mis-Moo (Box 11)
  - Moe, Henry Allen, 1959-1975 (Box 12)
  - Moldaver, Joseph, 1970-1975 (Box 12)
  - Mor-Mou (Box 12)
  - Moses, Robert L., 1954-1975 (Box 12)
  - Mra-Mu (Box 12)
  - Na-Neu (Box 12)
  - National Research Council, 1928-1931 1962 1967 (Box 12)
  - New-Ney (Box 12)
  - Ni (Box 12)
  - No-Ny (Box 12)
  - O (Box 12)
  - Oppenherimer, Robert, 1954-1963 (Box 12)
  - Pac-Par (Box 12)
  - Page, Irvine H., 1934-1971 (Box 12)
  - Pas-Pay (Box 13)
  - Pauling, Linus, 1952-1969 (Box 13)
  - Pea-Pen (Box 13)
  - Pep-Pet (Box 13)
  - Penfield, Wilder, 1934-1969 (Box 13)
  - Pf-Ph (Box 13)
  - Pic-Pow (Box 13)
  - Piel, Gerard, 1954-1974 (Box 13)
  - Piore, E.R., 1962-1973 (Box 13)
  - Pr-Pu (Box 13)
  - Pumphrey, R.J., 1934-1957 (Box 13)
  - Q (Box 13)
  - RGA-Ray (Box 13)
  - Rabi, I.I., 1948-1975 (Box 13)
  - Ravdin, I.S., 1931-1968 (Box 13)
  - Re (Box 13)
  - Reyniers, James A., 1958-1967 (Box 14)
  - Reynolds, S.R.M., 1927-1969 (Box 14)
  - Rh-Ri (Box 14)
  - Rob-Rog (Box 14)
  - Roh-Roy (Box 14)
  - Ru-Ry (Box 14)
  - Rubey, William W., 1951-1974 (Box 14)
  - Sa (Box 14)
  - Saturday Review, 1956-1960 (Box 14)
  - Sch (Box 14)
  - Schmitt, Francis O., 1934-1975 (Box 14)
  - Se (Box 14)
  - Seitz, Frederick, 1962-1972 1973-1975; 2 folders (Box 15)
  - Sha (Box 15)
  - She-Shu (Box 15)
  - Shelesnyak, M.C., 1951-1966 (Box 15)
  - Shilling, C.W., 1953-1956 (Box 15)
  - Shockley, William, 1951-1970 (Box 15)
  - Si (Box 15)
  - Sk-Sm (Box 15)
  - Sn-Sp (Box 15)
  - Society for Experimental Biology and Medicine, 1932-1936 (Box 15)
  - Solandt, D.W. and Barbara, 1933-1964 (Box 15)
  - Sta-Steg (Box 16)
  - Stei-Stet (Box 16)
  - Stella, G., 1931-1973 (Box 16)
  - Stengel, Alfred, 1935-1940 (Box 16)
  - Stev-Stew (Box 16)
  - Sti-Stu (Box 16)
  - Strauss, Lewis, 1958-1973 (Box 16)
  - Su-Sz (Box 16)
  - Ta-Te (Box 16)
  - Th (Box 16)
  - Ti-To (Box 16)
  - Tower, Sarah S., 1930-1966 (Box 16)
  - Tr-Ty (Box 16)
  - U (Box 17)
  - Va-Ve (Box 17)
  - Varian, Russell H., 1954-1958 (Box 17)
  - Vo (Box 17)
  - Wad-Wan (Box 17)
  - Wall, Joseph J. and family, circa 1942-1963 1964-1974; 2 folders (Box 17)
  - War-Wav (Box 17)
  - Ware, E.E., 1930-1937 (Box 17)
  - Wastl, Helene, 1931-1936 (Box 17)
  - Wea-Wel (Box 17)
  - Weaver, Warren, 1934-1966 (Box 17)
  - Welpley, Nyla, 1954-1970 (Box 18)
  - Wen-Wey (Box 18)
  - Wh-Wii (Box 18)
  - Whaley, W. Gordon, 1960-1976 (Box 18)
  - Whitehead, Edwin C., 1971 (Box 18)
  - Wigodsky, Herman S., 1957-1974 (Box 18)
  - Wilb-Will (Box 18)
  - Williams and Wilkins, 1928-1956 (Box 18)
  - Williams, H.B., 1927-1954 (Box 18)
  - Wilson, E.B., 1954-1958 (Box 18)
  - Wis-Wit (Box 18)
  - Woe-Wood (Box 18)
  - Wool-Wy (Box 18)
  - Y-Z (Box 18)
  - Zirkle, R.E., 1932-1936 (Box 18)
  - Zotterman, Yngve, 1929-1966 (Box 18)
  - Zuckerman, Solly, 1958-1967, undated (Box 18)
  - Unidentified correspondents (Box 18)